Guide to the New York State Council on the Arts Electronic Media and Film Program records, [ca. 1960-2011]
New York State Council on the Arts Electronic Media and Film Program records
- Reports and Catalogs
  - Reports, 1978 (Box 15, Volume 1)
    Minority Writers Conference on Television Production, III Report
  - National Endowment for the Arts: Media Arts Seminar (Ruby Rich), 1982 (Box 15, Volume 2)
  - The American Film Institute: Education Services, A White Paper, 1984 (Box 15, Volume 3)
  - Building Bridges: Cooperative Strategies for the 90s Report, 1990 (Box 15, Volume 4)
    Prepared by Margaret Cooper
  - Youth-Powered Video: A Hands on Curriculum for Teaching Documentary, 2006 (Box 15, Volume 5)
  - Academy for Educational Development: Youth Media Reporter Volume 1 and 2, 2007, 2008 (Box 15, Volume 6-7)
    Notes tipped in to volume 2 from Emerging trends in youth media, youth development and social justice (2009)
  - Ruby Rich: Articles and Presentations, 1988-2006, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
    Newspaper and magazine articles and addresses at meetings
  - Collections Management Technology Conference, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    conference information packet
  - Reports on Preservation of Video and Other Cultural Materials, 1996-2008 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    Includes the FY09 NYSCA Application support materials for Buffalo Media Resources (Squeaky Wheel) for the Upstate Preservation Workstation
  - The Digital Directory: Circuits@NYS, c. 1999 (Box 15, Volume 8)
  - National Alliance for Media Arts and Culture: Reports, 2000-2004 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    A Closer Look (200, 2003) and Deep Focus: A Report on the Future of Independent Media. Note: Correspondence between Karen Helmerson and Robyn Stein from 2005 tipped into report from 2004
  - Reports, 2002-2004 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    Why Fund Media; Ten Basic Responsibilities of Nonprofit Boards; The Information Commons: A public Policy Report and Unasked Questions; The ARCA Foundation 2004 Annual Report
  - Women Make Movies: Film and Video Catalog and Third World Newsreel Catalog, 2003-2005 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - American University: Center for Social Media, 2004-2006 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    various reports and guides including the Documentary Filmmakers' Statement of Best Practices in Fair Use
  - Grantmakers in Film and Electronic Media: Funders Briefings, 2005 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    Securing our Rights to Public Knowledge, Creativity, and Freedom of Expression and The Public Airwaves as Common Asset and Public Good
  - Reports, 2006; DVD-1053-1054 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    Mapping Public Radio's Independent Landscape: Opportunities for Innovation, Investing in Youth Media (2 copies, includes DVD) and Building a Media and Justice Communications Rights Movement
  - Benton Foundation: Reports, 2007 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    What's Going on in Community Media and Universal Affordable Broadband for all Americans
  - Grant Applications List, 2007 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    List of applicants for Audio and Interactive Media Categories with summery of supplemental materials such as project description, amount of request and Artist credentials.
  - Reports, 2008 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    Whose Media? Our Media! and Games for Change Festival
  - Reports, 2008-2009 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    Media Policy Communications Landscape Analysis material
  - Reports, 2009-2011, undated; DVD-1056 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    New Media Makers (including DVD); Journalism and Media Grant Making; Imagining the (UN)Thinkable
  - Videotape Collections, undated (Box 15, Folder 16)
    Museum of Modern Art (MOMA); Everson; Asian American Media Archive; WNET Programs in the NYSCA Video Archive; Media/Study/Buffalo
  - Blank letterhead for Circuits and Media Mirage: Coverage of the Gulf Crisis, undated (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Circuits@NYS Final Report, c. 1999 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    Oversize
  - Circuits@NYS Conference, 1998 (Box 19, Volume 1)
    Large Binder
  - Asian Cinevision Media Archives, 2007 (Box 19, Volume 2)
    Part of a grant proposal submission. Large Binder.
- Film Festival and Film Series Brochures and Schedules
  - African Diaspora Film Festival, 2003-2004 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - African Film Festival, 2003-2004 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Asian American International Film Festival, 2003, 2006-2008 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Brooklyn Arts Council International Film and Video Festival, 2004, 2006-2007 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Brooklyn International Film Festival, 2003-2010 (Box 16, Volume 1-7)
    missing 2007
  - Brooklyn International Film Festival, 2006 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Empire State Film Festival, 2000, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Film Fleadh - Irish International Film Festival, 2000, 2002-2003, 2006 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Havana Film Festival in New York, 2004-2009; DVD-1057 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    missing 2005. Includes DVD
  - Imagenation Film Festival, undated; DVD-1052 (Box 16)
  - Imagenation Film Festival, 2003-2005 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - ImageOut - Rochester Lesbian and Gay Film and Video Festival (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Independent Filmmakers Project (IFP), 2002-2010 (Box 16, Volume 8-16)
    IFP Market and Independent Film Week
  - Indo-American Arts Council Film Festival, 2005-2007 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Lake Placid Film Festival, 2001, 2004 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Long Island Film and Video Festival, 1994-1996 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Long Island Gay and Lesbian Film Festival, 2001-2003, 2006, 2008 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - MIX - New York Lesbian and Gay Experimental Film and Video Festival, c. 1999-2010 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    Programs for 1999, 2002-2003, 2007, 2009, 2010
  - Native American Film and Video Festival, 1997-2011 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    Programs for 1997, 2000, 2009, 2011
  - New Fest - New York Gay, Lesbian, Bisexual, and Transgender Film Festival, c. 2004-2010 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    Programs for 2004, 2006-2007, 2010
  - New York International Children's Film Festival, c. 2005-2010 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    Programs for years 2005, 2007, 2009-2010
  - New York Jewish Film Festival, 2007-2008 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - New York Latino Film Festival, 2004-2005 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - New York Turkish Film Festival, 2005-2010 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    Programs for 2005, 2007-2010
  - Pacifika - New York Hawaiian Film Festival, 1997, 2003-2006; DVD-1058 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    includes Pacifika 2004 trailer on DVD
  - Picture This...Film Festival, 2002, 2007-2008 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    "celebrates disability culture"
  - Prized Pieces International Black Film and Video Festival, 2001, 2004 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Robert Flaherty Film Seminar, 2004, 2007-2010 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - River to River Festival, 2008-2009 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Rochester Film Festival, 1998-2000 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Rural Route Film Festival, 2005-2007 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - South Asian International Film Festival, 2004-2005 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Syracuse International Film Festival, 2004, 2007-2009 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Tribeca Film Festival, 20108, 2010-2011 (Box 17, Volume 1-3)
    Filmmakers, Industry and Press (FIP) Guides and Film Fellows
  - Tribeca Film Festival, 2007 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    Press Kit for Karen Helmerson; Guide
  - Woodstock Film Festival, 2006-2010 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Festivals A-B, 2003-2008 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    African American Women in Cinema Film Festival (2006); African Diaspora Film Festival (2003); African Film Festival (undated); Big Sky Documentary Film Festival (2006); Black Maria Film Festival (2008)
  - Festivals C-F, c. 1999, 2006-2009 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    Canarias media Fest (2006); Cinemaeast Film Festival (2007); Dance in Cinema (2007); The Feminine Eye: Twenty Years of Women's Cinema (1999); Film Columbia Festival (2009)
  - Festivals H-L, 2004-2005, 2007 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    The Hamptons International Film Festival (2005); High Falls Film Festival (2005); Hip Hop Odyssy International Film Festival (2004); International Film Festival Rotterdam (2004); Karen Cooper Carte Blanche 40 Years of Documentary Premieres at Film Forum (2010); Little Foreign Film Festival (2007); Long Island International Film Expo (2008); Lower West Side Film Festival (2005)
  - Festivals M-R, c. 2001-2011 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    Margaret Meade Film and Video Festival (2009); New Italian Cinema Events (N.I.C.E.) (2005); New York Animation Festival (2001); New York Film Festival; New York Indian Film Festival (2011); Rochester Jewish Film Festival (2007); Rooftop Films (2003)
  - Set in Motion, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    The New York State Council on the Arts Celebrates 30 Years of Independents (3 copies)
  - Festivals S-W, c. 1998-2006 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    Stoney Brook Film Festival (1998); Sundance Film Festival (2006); Williamsburg Brooklyn Film Festival (2001)
  - Anthology Film Archives, 2009 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    Anthology Film Archives A Tribute Exhibition to Anthology Film Archives and Jerome Hill at the Maya Stendhal Gallery and Perspectives on Jerome Hill and Anthology Film Archives(booklets)
  - Alternating Currents - Beyond/In Western New York, 2010 (Box 17, Volume 4)
    exhibition catalog - organized by Albright-Knox Gallery, Buffalo also includes artwork from the CEPA Gallery, Hallwalls Gallery, Squeaky Wheel and others
  - Magazines, c. 1999-2007 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    Cinemedia (1999); Library of African Cinema (2002); Variety - Cannes Film Festival (2007)
- Media
  - TIG, undated; 3.5" floppy FD-3 (Box 18)
    IBM/DOS formatted
  - Various Projects, undated, c. 2004; 3.5" floppy FD-4 (Box 18)
    Team Notes and Projects; VA Committee Minutes 0010/0012; FY04 Guidelines MSC-VAP (for Debby). IBM/DOS formatted
  - FY04 Guidelines AIE - LIT, EMF - Q Works, c. 2004; 3.5" floppy FD-5 (Box 18)
  - Digital Directory - Cover (PDF), undated; 3.5" floppy FD-6 (Box 18)
  - NY Set in Motion, undated; 35mm F-955 (Box 18)
  - Set in Motion, undated; 16mm F-956 (Box 18)
  - I Love New York Arts - 2 spots, 1984; 16mm F-957 (Box 18)
  - Harry Smith Picks Up His Check, 1975; 16mm F-598 (Box 18)
  - unlabelled, undated; 16mm F-599 (Box 18)
    Film arrived exposed but unprocessed so it was processed in 2014. Images appear towards the very end of the reel.
  - Set in Motion: Program 2, Set B; Tapes 1-3, U-Matic V-7001-7003 (Box 18)
  - Set in Motion: Program 3, Set B; Tapes 1-2, U-Matic V-7004-7005 (Box 18)
  - Set in Motion: Program 5, Set A; Tapes 1-2, U-Matic V-7006-7007 (Box 18)
    Pass/Fail
  - Set in Motion: Program 6, Set A; Tapes 1-2, U-Matic V-7008-7009 (Box 18)
    TVTV:VTR: TVTV and Gerald Ford's America Chic to Sheik, In Our Own Backyards
  - Set in Motion: Program 7, Set A; Tapes 1-2, U-Matic V-7010-7011 (Box 18)
    Healthcare: Your Money or Your Life and Born to Be Sold
  - Set in Motion: Artists on Art - Parts 1-2, U-Matic V-7012-7013 (Box 18)
  - Set in Motion: Program 1, Set D, VHS V-7014 (Box 18)
  - Set in Motion: Program 2, Set C, VHS V-7015 (Box 18)
  - Set in Motion: Program 3, Set C and D, VHS V-7016-7017 (Box 18)
  - Set in Motion: Program 4, Set D, VHS V-7018 (Box 18)
  - Set in Motion: Jane Aaron, VHS V-7019 (Box 18)
  - Circuits at NYS - Reception, 1998; V-7021 (Box 18)
    Mini Digital Video Cassette
  - Alison Cornyn and Sue Johnson: 360degrees.org: Perspectives On the US Criminal Justice System, 2001; CD-2041 (Box 18)
    CD-Rom. Website Demo
  - National Endowment for the Arts: Operation Homecoming: Writing the Wartime Experience, 2004; CD-2042 (Box 18)
    Audio CD
  - Jordon Djurasevic, Mary - Millennium Film Workshop, Inc. (D 088), 2004; DVD-1049 (Box 18)
    Film: You Don't Know Jack
  - The Educational Video Center: Video Sampler, 2005; DVD-1050 (Box 18)
    Actions for Today: Blueprints for Tomorrow: Youth Organizing to Transform Education, Patriarchy is Malarkey and All That I Can Be
  - The Olana Partnership: Olana: Vision For the Future, DVD-1051 (Box 18)
  - Show the Right Thing: Aesthetics of Media, 1989; TR-10001-10003 (Box 19)
    3 copies
  - Show the Right Thing: Keynote Speaker - Toni Caoe Bambara, 1989; TR-10004-10005 (Box 19)
    2 copies
  - Show the Right Thing: Who is the Audience?, 1989; TR-10006-10008 (Box 19)
  - Show the Right Thing: Building an Audience (1 of 2), 1989; TR-10009-10011 (Box 19)
  - Show the Right Thing: Building an Audience (2 of 2), 1989; TR-10012-10014 (Box 19)
  - Show the Right Thing: Funding - The Exhibitor/Funding Relationship (1 of 2), 1989; TR-10015-10017 (Box 19)
  - Show the Right Thing: Funding - The Exhibitor/Funding Relationship (2 of 2), 1989; TR-10018-10020 (Box 19)
  - Show the Right Thing: Models of Third World Exhibition (1 of 2), 1989; TR-10021-10023 (Box 19)
  - Show the Right Thing: Models of Third World Exhibition (1 of 2), 1989; TR-10024-10026 (Box 19)
  - Show the Right Thing: Alliances, 1989; TR-10027-10029 (Box 19)
  - Show the Right Thing: Guest Curators and Touring Programs, 1989; TR-10030-10032 (Box 19)
  - Show the Right Thing: Anatomy of an Exhibition Program, 1989; TR-10033-10035 (Box 19)
  - Show the Right Thing: Funding for Community Exhibition, 1989; TR-10036-10038 (Box 19)
  - Show the Right Thing: Gatekeeping: The Implications of Choice, 1989; TR-10039-10041 (Box 19)
  - Show the Right Thing: Electronic Exhibition, 1989; TR-10042-10044 (Box 19)
  - Show the Right Thing: CPB, IPS, Minority Programming Consortia, 1989; TR-10045-10047 (Box 19)
  - Show the Right Thing: Politics of Culture, 1989; TR-10048-10050 (Box 19)
  - Show the Right Thing: Function of the Critic, 1989; TR-10051-10053 (Box 19)
  - Show the Right Thing: Challenging the Audience, 1989; TR-10054-10056 (Box 19)
  - Show the Right Thing: Conceptualizing Program Selections, 1989; TR-10057-10059 (Box 19)
  - Show the Right Thing: Closing - Future Initiatives, 1989; TR-10060-10062 (Box 19)
  - The August Coup Based on a play by Mikhail Gorbachev, undated; TR-10063 (Box 19)
  - North County - Helen Thorington, undated; TR-10064 (Box 19)
  - New American Radio Partial Perceptions - Helen Thorington, undated; TR-10065 (Box 19)
  - New Radio and Performing Arts, Inc.: Selections from the work of Helen Thorington, undated; TR-10066 (Box 19)
  - Angels Have Been Sent to Me an interactive art experience by Jerri Allyn, Music by Helen Thorington, TR-10067 (Box 19)
  - The Third Kingdom Suzan-Lori Parks, 1991-992; TR-10068 (Box 19)
  - If I Get Out Alive Bill Lichtenstein, 1999; TR-10069 (Box 19)
    Narrated by Diane Keaton
  - Little Odessa in Brooklyn Helen Borton, undated; TR-10070 (Box 19)
    Pilot for A Sense of Place
  - Sound Engine Bill and Mary Buchen, 1989; TR-10071 (Box 19)
  - Media Mirage: Media Coverage of the Gulf Crisis (set of 2), undated; TR-10072-10073 (Box 19)
    Media Consortium Against the War
  - Beebe's Bathysphere - Mark Magill - WJFF Radio Catskill, undated; TR-10074 (Box 19)
  - Censorship Plenary, undated; TR-10075 (Box 19)
  - Children, undated; TR-10076 (Box 19)
  - Dev Circuits, undated; TR-10077 (Box 19)
  - Specialized Festival, undated; TR-10078 (Box 19)
  - The Space You're In, undated; TR-10079 (Box 19)
  - Film in a Video Age, undated; TR-10080 (Box 19)
SEPARATED MATERIAL
Books - cataloged individually in the Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections
Braman, Sarah, Ed. Communication Researchers and Policy-making, 2003
Buckingham, David, Ed. Youth, Identity, and Digital Media, 2008
Computer Science and Telecommunications Board National Research Council. Broadband: Bringing Home the Bits, 2002
Franco, Debra. Alternative Visions: Distributing Independent Media in a Home Video World, 1990
Goodman, Steven. Teaching Youth Media: A Critical Guide to Literacy, Video Production and Social Change, 2003 (inscribed by author
Haller, Robert, Ed.Perspectives on Jerome Hill and Anthology Film Archives, 2005
Vollmer, Christopher and Geoffrey Precourt. Always On: Advertising, Marketing, and Media in an Era of Consumer Control, 2008